LAUREN NOELTNER

Atlanta, Georgia 30306

Phone: (404) 376-7192 | Email: laurennoeltner@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/lauren-noeltner-102b731a0 | GitHub:

https://www.github.com/LNoeltner1/ | Portfolio: https://lauren-noeltner.herokuapp.com/

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Junior Web Developer, bringing skills from previous experience in design, problem solving, and efficient communication. Authored the official employee manual for a chain of three stores, won the Above and Beyond award and won employee of the month on several occasions. Known for a willingness to go beyond expectations and determination, doing whatever it takes to successfully complete any task.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Page Design: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Foundation

Primary Language: JavaScript

Libraries/frameworks: React, Node, Express, jQuery, Handlebars, Axios, and many other

Node packages

Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, Sequelize, NoSQL

Development Tools: Version control/deployment with GitHub and Heroku, Git, Visual Studio

Code, MongoDB Atlas, Robo3T, MySQL Workbench, Postman, Chrome DevTools

PROJECTS

- Cryptic Encounters
 - Responsibilities: Front and Back End, dialogue mapping/logic, Design, Concept
 - Tech used: JavaScript, Handlebars, Nodejs, Express, MySQL, Foundation
 - Link to Github: https://github.com/LNoeltner1/cryptic-encounters
 - Link to Deployment: https://cryptic-encounter.herokuapp.com/
- GiddyltUp
 - Responsibilities: Front and Back End, REST/CRUD management, Design, Concept
 - Tech used: JavaScript, MongoDB, Express, React, Nodejs, Bootstrap, Animate.css
 - Link to Github: https://github.com/LNoeltner1/GiddyltUp
 - Link to Deployment: https://giddvitup-eg.herokuapp.com/
- Online/Offline Budget Tracker
 - Responsibilities: Front and Back End (solo project)
 - Tech Used: JavaScript, MongoDB, Nodejs, Express, Morgan
 - Link to GitHub: https://github.com/LNoeltner1/budget-tracker
 - Link to Deployment: https://budget-tracker-Inoeltner.herokuapp.com/

EXPERIENCE

Senior Team Lead

August 2020-Present Alpharetta, Georgia

Regal Entertainment Group

- Leading a large team of floor staff and team leads to provide high quality customer service
- Communicated with management to coordinate all theater operations and events

Team Lead

April 2019-August 2020

Regal Entertainment Group

Atlanta, Georgia

- Lead a team of 15 floor staff members to provide high quality customer service
- Assisted the General Manager with creating a checklist for all floor staff responsibilities to increase productivity and accountability.

Cast Member

February 2017-April 2019

Regal Entertainment Group

Atlanta, Georgia

- Collaborated with a team of 9 to provide high quality customer service
- Spent extra time cleaning and organizing to ensure a safe and healthy workspace for all
- Established and maintained positive relationships with customers by answering their questions and fixing any issues brought up

Assistant Manager

June 2016-August 2016

Victorious Vapors, LLC

Athens, Georgia

- Lead a small group of sales associates to ensure business efficiency and profitability
- Consistently maintained top sales numbers (>\$55,000 over 8 months)
- Established and maintained positive relationships with customers to ensure their loyalty
- Wrote employee manual in full to make the onboarding process quicker and more efficient

Sales Associate

August 2015-June 2016

Victorious Vapors, LLC

Athens, Georgia

• Developed a strong rapport with clients, creating a wide base of recurring, loyal customers

Dog-Sitter/Walker

May 2012-Present

Freelance pet-care business

Atlanta, Georgia

Established a successful business of pet-care with 100% client return rate

Kennel Technician

June 2008-August 2013

Briarcliff Animal Clinic

College Park, Georgia

- Assisted doctors with treatments, diagnoses, and surgeries to ensure pet health
- Maintained medical records to keep an accurate summary of the animal's condition

Key Accomplishments:

- Won Above and Beyond Award and Employee of the Month at different businesses
- Won several local and national painting awards

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development, Georgia Institute of Technology, November 2020

 A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS

Relevant courses, University of Georgia

Color and Composition, 3D Design, Research Statistics, Psychology courses, Physics